//Question bank
var questionBank = [
    {
        question : 'What colour is Darth Vader&#39;s light saber?',
        option : ['Red', 'Blue', 'Green', 'Yellow'],
        answer : 'Red'
    },
    {
        question : 'Who is the voice of Darth Vader in the original trilogy?',
        option : ['David Prowse', 'James Earl Jones', 'Mark Hamill', 'Harrison Ford'],
        answer : 'James Earl Jones'
    },
    {
        question : 'What was Darth Vader&#39;s name as a child?',
        option : ['Darth Vader', 'Han Solo', 'Anakin Skywalker', 'Boba Fett'],
        answer : 'Anakin Skywalker'
    },
    {
        question : 'What is the famous line said by Darth Vader?',
        option : ['"Luke, I am your father"', '"No, I am your father"', '"Who is your father?"', '"I am your mother"'],
        answer : 'No, I am your father'
    },
    {
        question : 'Who are Darth Vader&#39;s children?',
        option : ['Han and Leia', 'Luke and Leia', 'Luke and Han', 'He had no children'],
        answer : 'Luke and Leia'
    },
    {
        question : 'What planet did Darth Vader grow up on?',
        option : ['Hoth', 'Naboo', 'Tatooine', 'Tusken'],
        answer : 'Tatooine'
    },
    {
        question : 'Who was Darth Vader&#39;s grandchild?',
        option : ['Han Solo', 'Leia Organa', 'Luke Skywalker', 'Kylo Ren'],
        answer : 'No, I am your father'
    },
    {
        question : 'In what movie did Darth Vader tell Luke that he was his father?',
        option : ['A New Hope', 'The Empire Strikes Back', 'Return of the Jedi', 'The Last Jedi'],
        answer : 'The Empire Strikes Back'
    },
    {
        question : 'What is Darth Vader&#39;s theme song called?',
        option : ['March of the Resistance', 'Cantina Band', 'The Imperial March', 'Imperial Attack'],
        answer : 'The Imperial March'
    },
    {
        question : 'How many minutes of screen time did Darth Vader have in A New Hope?',
        option : ['12', '24', '36', '48'],
        answer : '12'
    },
    {
        question : 'Who convinced Darth Vader to turn to the dark side?',
        option : ['Darth Tyranus', 'Exar Kun', 'Palpatine', 'Darth Palgueis'],
        answer : 'Palpatine'
    },
    {
        question : 'What is Darth Vader&#39;s mother&#39;s name?',
        option : ['Tsumi', 'Rumi', 'Ahmi', 'Shmi'],
        answer : 'Shmi'
    },
    {
        question : 'What body part did Darth Vader cut off of Luke Skywalker?',
        option : ['Left hand', 'Right hand', 'Left leg', 'Right leg'],
        answer : 'Right hand'
    },
    {
        question : 'What Force power did Darth Vader use against his own officers?',
        option : ['Force choke', 'Force Grip', 'Mind Trick', 'Force Lightning'],
        answer : 'Force choke'
    },
    {
        question : 'Who was Darth Vader&#39;s wife?',
        option : ['Leia', 'Padme', 'Rey', 'Ahsoka'],
        answer : 'Padme'
    },
    {
        question : 'What age was Darth Vader when he turned to the dark side?',
        option : ['23', '24', '25', '26'],
        answer : '23'
    }
];

/*shuffle the question bank when the document loads */

shuffle(questionBank);
console.log(questionBank);

var question = document.getElementById('question');
var quizContainer = document.getElementById('quiz-container'); 
// var timeupmodal = document.getElementById('timeupmodal'); 
// var myModal = document.getElementById('myModal'); 
var scorecard = document.getElementById('scorecard');
var option0 = document.getElementById('option0');
var option1 = document.getElementById('option1');
var option2 = document.getElementById('option2');
var option3 = document.getElementById('option3');
var next = document.querySelector('.next');
var points = document.getElementById('score');
var span = document.querySelectorAll('span');
var currentQuestion = 0;
var score = 0;

//Function to display questions
function displayQuestion() {
    for (var a=0;a<span.length;a++){
        span[a].style.background='none';
    }
    question.innerHTML= 'Q.'+(currentQuestion+1)+' '+questionBank[currentQuestion].question;
    option0.innerHTML= questionBank[currentQuestion].option[0];
    option1.innerHTML= questionBank[currentQuestion].option[1];
    option2.innerHTML= questionBank[currentQuestion].option[2];
    option3.innerHTML= questionBank[currentQuestion].option[3];
    questionCount.innerHTML= "Question" + ' ' + (currentQuestion+1) + ' ' + 'of' + ' ' + (questionBank.length-6);
    // if(i<questionBank.length-6){
    //     scoreboard.style.display= 'block'
    // }
}

//Function to calculate scores
function calcScore(e){
    if(e.innerHTML===questionBank[currentQuestion].answer && score<questionBank.length){
        score= score+1;
        document.getElementById(e.id).style.background= 'limegreen';
    } else {
        document.getElementById(e.id).style.background= 'tomato';
    }
    setTimeout(nextQuestion,300);
}

//NEW Function to display next question
function nextQuestion(){
    var timeleft = 60;
    if(currentQuestion<questionBank.length-7){
        currentQuestion=currentQuestion+1;
        displayQuestion();
    } else {
        scoreboard.style.display= 'block'
        points.innerHTML= score+ '/'+ questionBank.length;
        quizContainer.style.display= 'none';
    }
}

//NEW Click events to next button
next.addEventListener('click',nextQuestion);

//OLD Function to display next question
// function nextQuestion(){
//     if(i<questionBank.length-1)
//     {
//         i=i+1;
//         displayQuestion();
//     } else {
//         points.innerHTML= score+ '/'+ questionBank.length;
//         quizContainer.style.display= 'none';
//         scoreboard.style.display= 'block'
//         delete window.alert
//     }
// }
//OLD Click events to next button
// next.addEventListener('click',nextQuestion);

//Back to Quiz button event
function backToQuiz(){
    location.reload();
}

//Function to check Answers
function checkAnswer(){
    var answerBank= document.getElementById('answerBank');
    
    var answers= document.getElementById('answers');
    answerBank.style.display= 'block';
    scoreboard.style.display= 'none';
    
    for(var a=0;a<(questionBank.length-6);a++) {
        var list= document.createElement('li');
        list.innerHTML= questionBank[a].answer;
        answers.appendChild(list);
    }
}
displayQuestion();

/** 
 * Countdown timer which shows a window alert 
 * if the player does not complete the quiz before the countdown ends
 * if the player does complete the quiz before the countdown ends, then the window alert does not show
 */ 
 document.getElementById("gameStart").addEventListener("click", function(){
    document.getElementById("question-buttons").style.display = "block"
    document.getElementById("welcome-text").style.display = "none"
    document.getElementById("gameStart").style.display = "none"
    document.getElementById("next").style.display = "none"
    var timeleft = 60;
    var currentQuestion = 0;
    var a=0;a<(questionBank.length-6);

    var downloadTimer = setInterval(function function1(){
    timeleft -= 1;
    document.getElementById("countdown").innerHTML = timeleft + 
    " " + "seconds remaining";
        if(timeleft <= -0){
            $("#myModal").modal();
            clearInterval(downloadTimer);
        } else if (timeleft >= 0, currentQuestion>questionBank.length-7){
            $("#myModal").modal('hide');
            clearInterval(downloadTimer);
            quizContainer.style.display= 'none';
            scoreboard.style.display= 'block';
        }
        }, 100);
});

/** 
 * Connected to the Reset button and 
 * reloads the page so the player 
 * can retsart the quiz and the timer.
 */ 
function refresh(){
    window.location.reload("Refresh")
  }

// Modal function
const overlay = document.querySelector("#overlay");
  document.querySelector("#show-modal-btn").
  addEventListener("click", () => {
      overlay.style.display = "block";
  })
  document.querySelector("#close-modal-btn").
  addEventListener("click", () => {
      overlay.style.display = "none";
  })
  const modalOverlay = document.getElementById("overlay")

  modalOverlay.classList.add('hide')


  function shuffle(array) {
    let currentIndex = array.length;
  
    // While there remain elements to shuffle...
    while (currentIndex != 0) {
  
      // Pick a remaining element...
      let randomIndex = Math.floor(Math.random() * currentIndex);
      currentIndex--;
  
      // And swap it with the current element.
      [array[currentIndex], array[randomIndex]] = [
        array[randomIndex], array[currentIndex]];
    }
  }
